紙牌屋
前情提要
翻譯   草草
翻譯   國士章魚X
翻譯   蘇小黛
翻譯   杏仁斯嘉麗
時間軸   知之
時間軸   壬虛浪影
后期   餓得慌
顧問   老杜
校對   草草
總監   草草
紙牌屋
人人影視傾情奉獻
第五季  第十二集
今天是你的生日
趁牙齒還在
快微笑一個
莉·哈維  筆記本
凱·杜蘭特  筆記本
馬·厄舍  手機
[標題]
湯姆·耶茨著
佩特羅夫嘲笑安德伍德所劃紅線
生日快樂
我覺得出現了泄密者
I think there's a leak.
安德伍德政府的
In the Underwood Administration.
我們怎能相信他說的話呢
How can we trust anything he says?
加勒特·沃克任總統期間一直在用藥
Garrett Walker was medicated while he was in office.
這我們都知道
We all know that.
-黨內警告  -不行
- Censure. - No.
我理解馬克的意思
I see Mark's point.
根本不可能阻止眾議院的共和黨人
There is no way to stop the Republicans in the House.
-你認識我多久了  -很久了
- How long have you known me? - Forever.
那你有多了解我
How well do you know me?
就算你克萊爾·安德伍德
How, in your wildest imagination,
再怎么盡情發動想象力
could you, Claire Underwood,
也不該以為我會接受這個
think I would be okay with this?
是我導致了你丈夫的死
I'm the reason your husband's dead.
你真覺得我不知道嗎  道格
You really think that I didn't know, Doug?
我操你不是因為我喜歡你
I'm not fucking you because I like you.
我操你是因為我恨你
I'm fucking you because I hate you.
"一位白宮內部人士透露
"A source deep within the White House...
安德伍德總統確實
confirms President Underwood
曾利用可疑情報
used questionable intelligence
使選舉陷入了混亂"
which threw the election into chaos."
你得離開
You need to leave.
這里就是容不下你了
There's just no place for you here anymore.
如果這是你的選擇
If that's what you choose.
真希望我能讓你改主意  凱茜
I really wish I could have changed your mind, Cathy.
-我...  -因為
- I just... - Because, you know...
這對你實在沒好處
you know, this is just not good for you.
跟委員會的談判
The negotiations with the committee
實在還太遠
are just too far down the road.
你答應見我是因為你聰明
Well, you agreed to see me because you're smart.
因為你是該有所疑慮
Because doubt is what you should be having.
凱茜  我尊敬你
Look, Cathy, I respect you.
否則我們也不會在一起這么久了
We wouldn't have lasted as long together if I didn't.
我丈夫在等我呢
My husband's waiting for me.
但你會出丑的
But you're gonna be made to look a fool.
沒必要侮辱我  弗蘭西斯
There's no need to insult me, Francis.
會有一堆證人反駁
Witness after witness is gonna rebut
你要說的一切
whatever you have to say.
我的證詞就是那樣
My testimony is what it is.
公眾輿論會自有公斷
It'll all be resolved in the court of public opinion.
是啊  但公眾會信誰呢
Yes, but who is the public going to believe?
你  還是恐怖分子電腦上的爆炸物殘留
You or explosive residue on a terrorist's computer?
凱茜  你的證詞會看上去像小氣的報復
Look, Cathy, your testimony's gonna seem petty and vengeful.
那你會怎么樣啊  還有什么前途
And then where is that gonna leave you? What prospects?
太遲了
It's too late.
-你得栽一跟頭  -什么
- You need to take a fall. - Excuse me?
委員會得等等
Look, the committee is just gonna have to wait.
反正再過兩周這都會過去
In two weeks, it's gonna be over anyway,
你就站錯隊了
and you're gonna be on the wrong side of this thing.
-走著瞧吧  -是啊
- Well, we'll see. - Yes, we will.
你先請
After you.
但我的話是真心的  凱茜
But I meant what I said, Cathy.
凱茜
Cathy?
救命  救命  國務卿摔倒了
Help! Help! The secretary has fallen!
你真走運
You're a lucky bastard.
直到今晚結束時才是
Oh, not until the end of the night.
或者該說早上了
Or should I say, the morning.
凱瑟琳·杜蘭特摔倒了  怎么回事
Catherine Durant fell? How?
人會摔倒  就這么簡單
Well, people fall. That's what they do.
是啊  在需要的時候
Yes, they fall when they need to.
你的新朋友還是會被彈劾的
Your new friend is still gonna get impeached.
希望到時候
Well, I hope I can still count on
參議員還是會支持我
the good senator's support when the time comes.
你很會打牌  馬克
You're a good card player, Mark.
你從不在牌桌上談公事
You never talk shop at the table.
總是提款的時候才說
It's always when you're cashing out.
我媽媽教得好
Well, my mother raised me well.
票數讓參議員越來越難做了
The numbers are getting harder and harder for the senator.
-為什么  -資金流入  電話打來
- Why is that? - The money and the calls coming in.
一個數字減少  另一個就增多
One number goes down, and the other one goes up.
參議員受到了壓力  來自哪里
The senator's feeling the heat, from where?
你回頭再來吧  我們到時談
Why don't you come in later. We can talk about it then.
不不  等一下
No, no, no. Wait a minute.
丹尼  我指著他的票呢
Danny... I'm counting on his vote.
-那別指望了  -不行
- Well, you can count it out. - No. No...
半數民主黨都是如此
And half of the Democrats as well.
別去想什么警告了  眾議院還未就
Forget about censure, the House hasn't even voted yet
彈劾狀表決呢
on articles of impeachment.
你不是唯一在做參議院工作的人
You're not the only one working the Senate.
-有人想趕走弗蘭西斯  -我問是誰
- Someone wants Francis out. - And I'm asking you who.
你混了很久了
You've been around a long time.
沒人會告訴你怎么投票
Nobody tells you how to vote.
只會說你不聽他們的會有什么下場
They just tell you what happens if you don't go their way.
石油每桶50美元
Oil's at $50 a barrel.
沒人對此滿意
Nobody's happy with that.
我們本打算今天對司法委員會
We were hoping to bring you live coverage
聽證會進行直播
of the judiciary hearing today.
但由于杜蘭特國務卿
But given the postponement
意外地無法出席  而使聽證會延期
due to Secretary Durant's unexpected absence,
我們將改為
we'll be switching to
轉播軍事委員會的會議
the Armed Services Committee meeting instead,
-女士  -多位軍隊高官
- Ma'am? - where several top military officials...
將報告哈里發國愈增的威脅
...are citing the increased threat of ICO...
今天的日程
Today's schedule.
我覺得您會想看這個
And I thought you might wanna see this.
是湯姆·耶茨的信
It's a note from Tom Yates.
另外
Oh, and reminder,
我們得繼續士兵康復項目
we have to get back to the Soldier Recovery Project.
和平
Peace.
那是我們的目標
That's our goal.
通過和平  我們得找到新的前進之途
And through peace, we must find a different way forward.
伊斯瑪特上校是民主派領袖
Colonel Ismat is the leader of the Democratic faction,
竭力解放敘利亞人民
dedicated to freeing the Syrian people.
由于杜蘭特國務卿暫時無法繼續工作
And since Secretary Durant is temporarily sidelined,
我今天要暫代她  因為美國政府
I'm stepping in today because the American government
支持一切邁向穩定的堅實腳步
supports any concrete steps toward stability.
如果得到確認  敘利亞沖突中
If it is determined that chemical or biological weapons
用到了生化武器
have been used in the Syrian conflict,
那么從此刻起
then from this moment forward,
美國將有道德義務插手
the United States will be morally obligated to intervene.
所以  敘利亞總統算就此得到警告了
So, the Syrian president should consider himself on notice.
總統先生  鑒于眾議院
Mr. President, given the potential outcome
可能提交彈劾狀
that the House will affirm articles of impeachment,
現在插手中東沖突合適嗎
is this the right time to wade into a Middle Eastern conflict?
這個問題與主題無關  但我還是回答吧
Well, the question's off subject, but I'll answer it.
首先  投票就不會進入參議院
First of all, the vote is never gonna get to the Senate.
這只是毫無意義的黨爭鬧劇
It's a senseless partisan circus.
我的關注點是做好我的工作
My focus is to remain doing my job,
也就是確保美國人民繁榮富強
which is to ensure prosperity for the American people,
并努力實現
and to try to achieve...
對不起  和平怎么說的來著
I'm sorry, how did you say it again? Peace?
-和平  -和平
- Salam. - Salam...
這就是我們在努力爭取的  和平
That's what we're trying to broker here. Salam.
我們給總統和伊斯瑪特上校時間會面吧
So let's give the president time to meet with Colonel Ismat.
我會在媒體接待室接受提問
I'll take follow-up questions in the press briefing room.
或許我太沒想象力  但那就是夜晚的大海啊
Maybe I'm being too literal, but that's the sea at night.
-你喜歡嗎  -我更喜歡紅的
- Do you like it? - I prefer the reds.
我在泰特現代藝術館看過他的展出
I... I saw a show of his at the Tate Modern.
但我無法把人和藝術品分開
I have trouble separating the man from the art, though.
他是個壓抑的人  你肯定也知道
He was, uh, depressive, as I'm sure you know.
你能看出他在抵抗心魔
You can see him fighting his demons.
納澤先生到了
So Mr. Nasser has arrived?
到了  在四季酒店等我的電話
Uh, here and waiting for my call at the Four Seasons.
我就是覺得這恐怕不好
Well, I just... I don't think it's a good idea
我們政府的一位成員
for anyone in our administration
去見哈里發國的成員
to be meeting with a member of ICO.
他不是成員
He's not a member.
他跟尤瑟夫·艾哈邁迪是同學
He went to school with Yusuf Al Ahmadi.
他是律師  他代理人和組織
He's a lawyer. He represents people, organizations.
-就一個組織  -而且他是要見我
- One organization, to be exact. - And he's meeting with me.
為什么有這樣的猶豫
Where is all this hesitation coming from?
對不起  我頭好疼
I'm sorry. I just have a splitting headache.
胡蔓藤
Gelsemium.
治偏頭痛的  我經常犯
For migraines. I get them all the time.
是中藥
It comes out of China.
別擔心  是草藥
But don't worry, it's herbal.
但你得注意用量
You have to be careful of the dosing, though.
就兩滴
Just two drops.
我看到的是純粹的感覺
You know, it's pure feeling for me.
光明對黑暗
Light versus dark.
和他們的交界線
And that line where they meet.
總統根本不知道
The president had no idea.
你跟麥卡倫先生很親密
You were close to Mr. Macallan?
是的  但那不代表我知道他的企圖
Yes, but that doesn't mean that I knew what he was up to.
那你怎么知道總統與此無關
But then how do you know the president wasn't involved?
我是最后見到艾丹的人  他向我坦白了
I was the last person to see Aidan. He confessed to me.
他秘密利用了國安局和外國情報監視法法庭
He secretly used the NSA, FISA,
操縱了選民
to manipulate the electorate.
我們要會見律師
We're meeting with counsel
打磨剩下的證詞
to perfect the rest of the testimony.
只要沒人能拿出駁斥你的證據就行
As long as no one has anything that contradicts you.
不會有的
No one does.
回來的感覺好嗎  莉安
Does it feel good to be back, LeAnn?
是的  謝謝
It does. Thank you.
我知道克萊爾很高興
Well, I know Claire is delighted
你能回到她辦公室
to have you back in her office.
副總統的會面
Will you let me know as soon
一結束你就告訴我
as  the vice president's meeting is done?
好  先生
Yes, sir.
我討厭她回來  她撒謊
I hate having her back. She's a liar.
你覺得麥卡倫給了她什么做保險嗎
You think Macallan gave her something for insurance?
她不肯承認  但是的  我覺得有
She won't admit it. But, yeah, I think he did.
等委員會啟動后  讓她去作證吧
Let's get her in front of that committee when they're up and running.
到時她就必須決斷了
Then she'll have to make a choice.
格林有些不敢作證
Green is hesitant to testify.
要不是我知道
You know, if I didn't know better,
我會以為他是泄密者呢
I'd think he was the leak.
他知道的信息
He has far more information
實在太多了
than anyone should be comfortable with.
另外理查德森參議員還沒回我電話
Also, Senator Richardson hasn't called me back.
上校  抱歉剛剛不得不走開
Colonel, my apologies for the interruption.
我想向你保證  你的擔憂就是我的擔憂
And I want to assure you that your concerns are my concerns.
艾哈邁迪兄弟
The Ahmadi brothers...
他們所想的激進伊斯蘭是維持不下去的
their idea of radical Islam is unsustainable.
納澤代表了厭倦了死亡的哈里發國分子
Nasser represents members of ICO who are tired of death.
他們基本上控制了
They essentially control
多個油田和多家精煉廠
numerous oil fields and several refineries.
納澤已經見過了敘利亞總統
Nasser already met with the president of Syria.
還有佩特羅夫的外交部長
And Petrov's minister of foreign affairs.
他想做個交易
He's looking for a deal.
他們想在這個十年內成為
They wanna be a corporation trading on the Dow
上市公司
before the decade is over.
他們想加入石油輸出國組織
They wanna be a part of OPEC.
那么伊斯瑪特上校和敘利亞人民呢
So where does that leave Colonel Ismat and the Syrian people?
能保命  只要我們調兵
Alive... once we're on the ground.
是啊  但俄羅斯已被請去  我們需要理由
Yes, but Russia was invited in. We need cause.
敘利亞總統用毒氣對付了人民
The Syrian president has gassed civilians.
他還會再那么做的  我敢保證
He will again. I can guarantee it.
伊斯瑪特上校會確保這一點
Colonel Ismat will make sure of it.
他會在政權內部煽動襲擊
He'll instigate an attack from the regime.
我們派部隊過去  不動哈里發國的資源
We put troops on the ground, leave ICO resources alone...
納澤會確保他們配合
and Nasser will make sure they cooperate.
怎么了
What is it?
你擔心他會被彈劾嗎
Are you afraid he's gonna be impeached?
因為  他很可能會的
'Cause there's a good chance that he will be.
這就是你想等的原因嗎  因為
Is that why you wanna wait? 'Cause...
我可以推遲一切
I can make it all wait.
戴維斯女士和我的談話很有成效
Ms. Davis and I had a very productive talk.
我告訴了她
I let her know that
我們的插手是以艾哈邁迪的被捕為交換條件的
our involvement is contingent on the delivery of Ahmadi.
是啊  但我能采取行動的時間
Yes, but the window is closing for me
越來越少了
to be able to act on this.
司法委員會可不會等
Judiciary's not gonna wait.
想要這個起作用  時不我待
For this to be effective, it has to be now or never.
我會讓她聯絡納澤先生
I'll have her reach out to Mr. Nasser.
那另一件事呢
And, uh, what about the other matter?
莉安嗎
You mean LeAnn?
戴維斯女士今天下午會跟她談
Ms. Davis will speak to her later this afternoon.
你聽到總統的話了
You heard the president.
我還在白宮
Uh, I'm still at the White House.
-等我們插手敘利亞  -先生
- Once we get into Syria... - Sir,
我是肖恩·杰弗瑞斯
my name is Sean Jeffries.
-我跟...  -嗯  我知道你是誰
- I work with... - Yes, I know who you are.
肖恩
Sean...
我知道湯姆·漢默施密特在查什么
I know what Tom Hammerschmidt is working on.
杰弗瑞斯先生  如果你想預約  我可以安排
Mr. Jeffries, if you need an appointment, I can arrange one...
先生  我只想占用您片刻時間
Sir, if I could. Just a moment of your time.
是機密
It's confidential.
如果你不介意  我們想用一下這個房間
Oh, if you don't mind, we'd like this room for a moment.
給你30秒  但你開始前
You have 30 seconds. But before you start,
是我錯了嗎  格雷森先生不是你的上級嗎
am I mistaken, or is Mr. Grayson your superior?
是的  對不起  但是
Yes, I'm sorry, but...
湯姆認為  道格·斯坦普和您  先生
Tom thinks Doug Stamper and yourself, sir,
跟佐伊·巴恩斯之死有關
are somehow involved with the death of Zoe Barnes.
漢默施密特先生得到了一部
And Mr. Hammerschmidt has a phone
有人給巴恩斯小姐的手機
that was given to Ms. Barnes.
手機只打過一個號碼  是您的號碼
It called only one number, and that number was yours.
看來這個號碼
Now, it seems that number
在她死時帶的手機里也有
has shown up on the phone that she died with.
雖然手機受損  但現在有技術
It was damaged, but there's technology now
可以讓他們獲取她死前
that will give them access to the data
手機上的數據
leading up to the day of her death.
內存  電話  短信
Its internal memory. Calls, texts.
都在上面
It's all there.
你什么時候開始為我們工作的
When did you start with us?
一周前
A week ago.
是副總統讓你加入的
And it was the vice president who brought you on?
是的
That's correct.
一周
A week...
你已經
and you're already having
跟總統談機密了
confidential conversations with the president.
是的
I am.
如果你再聽到別的消息  直接來找我
If you hear anything else, you come directly to me.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
不管你怎么說  這是偽證罪
Whatever you say it is, it's perjury.
偽證
Oh, perjury, huh?
這是你的底線嗎
That's where you draw the line?
我不干了
I'm done.
案子已經準備好了
The case has already been prepared.
穆罕默德·卡拉比的電腦上找到了熵炸藥
TATP was found on Muhammed Kalabi's computer.
杜蘭特國務卿怎么想根本不重要
It doesn't matter what Secretary Durant believes or not.
一個是推測  一個是事實
One is speculation, and the other is fact.
事實  是嗎  那是事實嗎
Fact? Really? Is that what it is?
如果聽上去像事實  那就是事實
If it sounds like a fact, then it is a fact.
卡拉比鍵盤上有爆炸殘留物
Kalabi had explosive residue on his keyboard.
你知道聯調局其他人都受夠總統了
You know the rest of the bureau is done with the president.
我沒跟他們說話  我在跟你說話
I'm not talking to them. I'm talking to you.
他們都睜一只眼閉一只眼  但還能持續多久
They've looked the other way, but for how much longer?
道格  他完了
Doug... he's done.
那我怎么辦
Where does that leave me?
這就是我們在談的
That's what we're discussing right now.
你知道總統怎么想嗎
Do you know what the president thinks?
他覺得你是泄密者
He thinks you're the leak.
那倒好了
I wish.
我給你點時間收回那句話
I'm going to give you a moment to take that statement back.
我會做我該做的  我去作證
I'll do what I have to do. I'll testify.
但總統完了
But the president is done.
他在失去支持  你能感覺到
He's losing support. You can smell it.
你在給別人效力嗎
Are you working for anyone else?
-你在給別人效力嗎  -沒有
- Are you working for anyone else? - No.
我也不想知道別的
And I don't wanna know anything else.
我已知的已經讓我煩透了
I'm tired of what I know.
就當我是個傳話的
Consider me a proxy.
-什么  -他們不想問  但我來問
- What? - They don't wanna ask, but I will.
你必須完全投入
You need to be fully committed,
也就是說  你得完全透明
which means being fully transparent,
也就是說  你得交出你手上的東西
which means handing over what you have.
能拜托你等等嗎
Slow down, will you, please?
我想回家了  戴維斯女士
I'd like to get home, Ms. Davis.
莉安  莉安
LeAnn? LeAnn?
有時候  我會去賓館過夜
Some nights, I go to a hotel to sleep,
就為了換換地方  不在家待著
just to get out of my apartment.
這個城市的女人  都要高度警惕
Being a woman in this city, the vigilance it takes...
你不能犯任何錯誤  不能有一絲分神
You're not allowed to make a mistake... get distracted.
代價很沉重
It's a heavy price.
神經緊繃年復一年
To be on the edge that way for years and years...
我的證詞不會讓人失望的
My testimony won't disappoint.
就算總統和副總統滿意吧
Well, the president and vice president are pleased, I assume.
但你覺得還要多久
But how long before the media
媒體就會開始追問麥卡倫的死
starts asking questions about Macallan's death,
以及他怎么死的
and how he was killed?
順便說一句  你的槍在我這里
I have your gun, by the way.
-晚安  -沒錯  晚安
- Good night. - Yes, good night.
克萊爾
Claire?
-怎么了  -克萊爾
- Yes? - Claire?
什么事
What's the matter?
漢默施密特又有了個新理論
Hammerschmidt has a new theory.
他認為道格·斯坦普和我殺了佐伊·巴恩斯
He thinks Doug Stamper and I killed Zoe Barnes.
他們可能接觸到了我的手機短信內容
They may have access to my cell phone, to my texts.
白宮有人在向漢默施密特泄密
Someone in this White House is talking to Hammerschmidt
現在又是這個
and now this.
道格啊
Oh, Doug.
可憐的道格
Poor Doug.
是啊
Yes.
他怎么這么倒霉
He's an unlucky person.
他一直如此
Always has been.
先生  參議員的支持動搖了
Sir, the senator's support is wavering.
道格  我是克萊爾
Doug, it's Claire.
抱歉  我...
I'm sorry, I...
弗蘭西斯和我在想
Francis and I were wondering
你明晚能不能到宅邸來一趟
if you could come up to the residence tomorrow evening.
吃個晚飯
For dinner.
最近發生了這么多事
It'll give us a chance to
我們也好歇一歇  喘口氣
take a breath with all that's been happening.
喂
Hello?
生日快樂
Happy birthday.
-你是誰  -拜托  你肯定猜到了吧
- Who is this? - Come on, you must know by now.
-我不知道  -艾丹·麥卡倫
- No, I don't. - Aidan Macallan.
查查他是怎么利用外國情報監視法裁決的
Look into how he used and abused the FISA ruling.
我們怎么認識的
How do we know each other?
別問了
Now come on.
如果我告訴你
If I told you that,
我還要怎么繼續幫你
how can I possibly keep helping you?
你難道不希望我幫你嗎
And don't you want me to help you?
可我們在哪見面  告訴我這個就行
But where do we meet? Just give me that.
-泥巴里  -等等
- In the muck. - Wait.
佐伊·巴恩斯的死不是意外
Zoe Barnes' death was not an accident.
道格·斯坦普殺了她
Doug Stamper killed her.
但你已經知道了
But you already know that.
不  別掛  別掛
No, don't hang up. Don't hang up.
司法委員會可能
The Judiciary Committee may be
還希望杜蘭特國務卿盡快恢復
hoping Secretary Durant recovers.
但全世界都在關注
But the rest of the world is waiting to see
敘利亞總統將如何回應
how the Syrian president responds
安德伍德總統劃下的紅線
to President Underwood's line in the sand.
與此同時  莫斯科稱總統此份聲明
Moscow, meanwhile, calls the president's statements,
是"即將倒臺之人的絕望之舉"
"The desperate act of a man on his way out of office."
你和你哥哥還有聯系嗎
Are you in contact with your brother?
沒有
No.
也就周末吧  偶爾過過生日
Sundays. Occasional birthday.
我還以為你們兩個要更親近些
I thought you were closer than that.
沒有  只有有麻煩時我們才會找對方
No. We usually only speak when one of us is in trouble.
所以我才打聽一下
Well, that's why I ask,
因為越是這種時候  我們就越需要支持
'cause in times like these, we all need support.
我會請律師
Well, I'll have counsel.
不  你得請最好的律師
No, you'll have the best lawyers.
什么都得最好的  頂尖的
The best of everything. The best.
你還想再來些魚嗎
Would you like some more fish?
不了  謝謝
No, thank you.
《先驅報》手里的料都只是間接的
Whatever the Herald has is circumstantial.
當然
Of course.
沒人知道她到底遭遇了什么
No one knows what really happened to her,
永遠也不會有人知道
and no one ever will.
是這樣  道格
But, look, Doug...
今晚我和克萊爾請你來的原因
The reason that Claire and I invited you over tonight
是因為我們希望你知道你對我們多么重要
is because we want you to know how much you mean to us.
對我們兩個都是
To both of us.
好  先生
Yes, sir.
在我們說別的事之前
Before we say anything else,
我們只想明白無誤地確認
we just wanted to be absolutely certain that...
你知道這一點
you knew that.
當然
Of course.
我們要面臨的
What we're up against,
這個政府要面臨的
what this administration is facing...
也是我要面臨的
Well, what I'm facing...
即便我們都相信
Even though both of us believe that
我被起訴的可能微乎其微
there's very little chance that I could ever be indicted,
我們仍然
we still...
得想辦法
have to find a way to
徹底解決這整件事
remove this entire issue from the table.
我不能再跟這事有牽連了
I just can no longer be associated with this.
我會辭職  并繼續處理此事
I'll resign while I'm dealing with this.
我覺得這可能還不夠
I think this is going to require more than that.
我會發表聲明
Well, I'll make a statement...
說這是人身攻擊式的政治手段
and blame it on the politics of personal destruction.
不  道格  恐怕這些仍不夠
No, Doug, I'm afraid that's just not going to be enough.
我們得轉移懷疑目標
We have to shift... the suspicion.
我們需要你...
We need you to...
我們需要你讓自己跟佐伊·巴恩斯的死掛上鉤
We need you to implicate yourself in the death of Zoe Barnes.
先別激動  聽我說
Now, before you react, just listen.
目前你是最有可能的人選
You are the most likely candidate at this point.
你當時心煩意亂  還酗酒
You were distraught, you were drinking.
我說不好
The... I don't know.
我們會編一些事出來  然后泄漏出去
We'll make up some story, and then we'll leak it.
你忠心耿耿  你那么做是為了我
You... you were loyal, you did it for me.
你忠誠過了頭  采取了極端手段
You were too loyal. You went too far.
然后  到最后  毫無疑問
And... and then, in the end, there'll be no question...
我失陪一下好嗎
Can you excuse me?
這要么是哪個怪胎想搏頭條
Well, it's either a crank looking for a headline,
要么就是內部人士在說真話
or someone on the inside telling the truth.
你感覺是什么
What's your sense?
他知道生日卡的事
He knew about the birthday cards.
我說不好
I don't know.
也許重點在于這電話
Maybe the story is the call.
那些閃存盤  泄密本身
The flash drives. The leaks themselves.
如果我們點出泄密的事
If we call out the leaks,
他可能就不會再聯系我了
he may stop contacting me.
還有麥卡倫的事  那真是條線索嗎
And the Macallan business, is that even a real lead?
這些網站什么都不會承認的
None of these sites will admit to anything.
因為這太丟人了
Because it's an embarrassment.
多個選情對安德伍德不利的郡的
An overwhelming amount of Underwood material
社交媒體用戶  爆出了大量
was reported by social media users in counties
安德伍德的材料
that he was expected to lose.
但我聯系的所有人
But anyone I reach out to
都不想談論此事
does not wanna be talking about this.
泄密者說那是未經授權的國內監控
The leak said it was unauthorized domestic surveillance.
政府只需要搬出"恐怖活動"
All the administration has to say is "terror,"
看起來就正當了
And they seem justified.
他可不是在鏟除恐怖分子
He wasn't rooting out terrorists.
他是想贏得選舉
He was trying to win an election.
國務卿正好撞了頭可太巧了
And very convenient that the Secretary of State hits her head.
你現在聽起來像是陰謀論...
Now you sound like a conspiracy...
我不是陰謀論者
I'm not a conspiracy theorist.
我試圖想象他是怎么想的
I try to imagine what it's like inside his mind,
如果我是他  我會怎么做
what I would do if I were him.
我跟你們說  這是各種...
And I'm telling you, it is all sorts of...
他沒有意識形態  沒有道德方向
He has no ideology. No North Star.
這難道不是最可怕的嗎
Isn't that the scariest thing of all?
湯姆  你覺得佐伊·巴恩斯是被謀殺的嗎
Tom, do you think Zoe Barnes was murdered?
一個27歲的人失足撞上火車的概率有多大
How often does a 27-year-old fall in front of a train?
-那好吧  我們去證明它  -好
- All right, then. Let's prove that. - All right.
怎么了
What's wrong?
道格·斯坦普的辦公室來電了
Doug Stamper's office called.
他們想安排見面
They wanna set up a meeting.
盡快吧
Soon as possible.
這是好事
This is good.
不管你男友今早從你手機里讀到了什么
Whatever your boyfriend read off your phone this morning
都傳到了正確的人的耳朵里
made its way to the right person.
我不知道我還能堅持多久
I don't know how much longer I can do this.
你只是在騙一個騙子
You're lying to a liar.
你無法從佐伊死時的手機上得到任何信息
You can't get anything off the phone Zoe died with.
他們只要相信我們能做到就行了
They just need to believe we can.
這到底是什么工作
What is this job?
跟以前不一樣了
Not what it used to be.
我不希望你反應過度
I don't want you to overreact.
但湯姆一直在繼續寫作
But Tom kept writing.
看來他終于完成他的書了
It seems he finally finished his book.
而且他暗示了一些事
And he alludes to things.
什么叫"暗示了一些事"
What do you mean "Alludes to things"?
我不知道  相關行都被涂黑了
I don't know. Lines are blacked out.
就像被編輯過
It's like it's redacted.
時不時的有一些段落
There are paragraphs here and there...
你跟他說過什么
What did you tell him?
他知道些什么
What does he know?
他給任何人看過嗎  寄給過任何人嗎
Has he shown this to anyone? Sent it to anyone?
-出版商  媒體  -我不知道
- Publishers, the press? - I don't know.
那你知道什么
Well, what do you know?
我來處理他  我只是想跟你說一聲
I will handle him. I just wanted you to be aware.
-媽了個逼的  -我說了我會處理的
- Son of a bitch. - I said I'll take care of it.
不  我來處理
No, I'll take care of it.
你躲得遠遠的
You stay a million miles away from this.
你怎么會這么蠢
How could you be so stupid...
動了真情
to fall in love?
這事還沒提交表決
This thing isn't on the floor yet,
我們就已經失去參議員的支持了
and we're losing senators.
失去了幾個吧  不過
We're losing some maybe, but...
參院最討喜的地方也是我最討厭的地方
What I like about the Senate is what I hate.
傳染性
It's contagious.
只要一個人有了什么想法
One of 'em gets an idea,
立馬就會像流感一樣傳遍全院
and it spreads through the body like a flu.
我再想想辦法
I'll look into it.
總共就100個人  我們只需要過半
There's 100 of 'em. All we need is half.
我能躺下嗎
Can I just lay down?
-最好不要  -我就躺幾分鐘
- I don't think that's a good idea. - Just for a few minutes.
我他媽快累死了  我得想想
I'm just so fucking tired, and I need to think.
你得想什么
Why do you need to think?
他給你的那些東西  你拿在手里越久
The longer you hang on to whatever he gave you,
你的處境就越危險
the more danger you're in.
你錯看局勢了
You're reading this wrong.
你以為那是保險  其實不是
You think it's some kind of insurance, but it's not.
莉安
LeAnn...
不管總統出了什么事
Whatever happens to the president,
都不是你  或者我的錯
it's not your fault, or mine.
-你以為我無關緊要嗎  -我可沒這么說
- You don't think I make a difference? - I didn't say that.
還是你覺得我不夠投入
You don't think that I'm dedicated enough?
太投入了
Too dedicated.
過了就有問題了  會讓你一葉障目
That can be a problem. That can make you blind.
你根本不知道
You have no idea...
我做了不可原諒的事  莉安
I've done something unforgivable, LeAnn.
什么
What?
我殺了佐伊·巴恩斯
I killed Zoe Barnes.
你為什么要這么說
Why would you say that?
我只是想保護她
All I ever tried to do was keep her safe.
她說她想就此消失
She said she wanted to be invisible.
我知道這根本不可能
I knew it wasn't possible.
我知道她要消失
I knew that she would only ever go away...
就得我親自動手
if I made sure of it.
我不信你
I don't believe you.
你當然信
Yes, you do.
相信我  這是我活該
Believe me... I deserve this.
佐伊·巴恩斯落軌被地鐵撞死了
Zoe Barnes fell in front of a train.
調查結果是意外事故
It was ruled an accident.
是我把她從站臺上推下去的  然后我就走了
I pushed her off the platform and I walked away.
我知道你聯系了布莉姬特·柯恩
I know you reached out to Bridget Cohen.
把我肝臟的來頭告訴她或是委員會
Telling that committee or her how I got my liver
對政府  對你  都沒有一絲好處
is not going to help this administration or you.
我告訴你做什么有好處
But here is what is going to help.
我要你去找委員會
This is what you're going to tell that committee
這么說道格·斯坦普
about Doug Stamper.
你就住這兒
You actually live here?
我不經常住
Well... I'm not here that much.
偶爾讓我朋友來住住
I let friends use it now and again.
-謝謝你的謹慎  -應該的
- Thanks for your discretion. - Of course.
我不會待太久
I won't be too long.
你慢慢來
Take your time.
如果需要什么  我隨叫隨到
If you need anything, I'll be on call.
他是講道理的
He's reasonable.
是啊  他必須這樣
Yeah, he needs to be.
他們也沒怎么查
They didn't look that hard.
特勤局知道我沒什么好隱瞞的
The Secret Service knows I have nothing to hide.
他就在樓下
He's downstairs.
別客氣
Make yourself at home.
我小時候可喜歡捉迷藏了
I used to love to hide as a kid.
我總是藏得非常好
I was really good at it.
我總能找到最隱蔽的藏身處
I could always choose the best places.
從來沒被抓到過
Nobody ever found me.
有一次大家干脆不玩了
One time, everybody just gave up.
所以我在那兒躲了整整13個小時
So I stayed put for, like, 13 hours straight.
你想要什么
What do you want?
他說如果我同意  我絕不會后悔的
He said I wouldn't regret it... if I said yes.
弗蘭西斯
Francis.
就是想當初  我同意
When I agreed to write the book
寫他起家的故事的時候
about his origin story way back when.
那他現在可后悔請你了
Well, he regrets asking you now.
我同意  是因為我總是非常喜歡
I said yes 'cause I have always been a sucker
聽別人是怎么講他們自己的
for what people tell themselves about themselves.
誰還有手稿
Who has the manuscript?
只有你
You do.
出版商呢
And publishers?
還沒給
Not yet.
所以你覺得如何
So what did you think?
有好多段落你都劃掉了  湯姆
There are huge sections blacked out, Tom.
你把我們描繪成了怪物
You portrayed us like a couple of monsters.
-我沒這么寫  -你也不用寫出來
- I never used that word. - You didn't have to.
我們剛認識時  在從莫斯科回來的飛機上
On the flight back from Moscow, not long after we met...
你和弗蘭西斯大吵了一架
you and Francis had a fight.
吵得很兇
A real knock down.
我告訴弗蘭西斯我聽見了吼聲
I told Francis I heard the yelling,
但沒聽清說什么
but not the words.
但
But...
你說你們殺了人
you said you were murderers.
他說你們是適者生存
He said you were survivors.
我害怕到這里來
I was dreading coming here.
-為什么  -你不能出版  湯姆
- Why? - You can't publish it, Tom.
我也不想
I'd rather not.
那為什么  錢嗎
So, what? Money?
對  但是夠了
Yeah... but enough.
足夠讓我消失一陣了
Enough so I can really get lost for a while.
靜一靜  讓我好好想想該何去何從
Buy some time till I figure out what I'm gonna do next.
我們可以商量個對策的
We can figure something out.
當然
I bet.
那些你涂黑的部分
You know, those parts you blacked out, that's...
-除了你我誰都沒告訴過  -我知道
- I've never told anyone but you. - I know.
我什么都知道
I know everything.
但你要的不就是這樣嗎
But isn't that what you wanted?
我想念撫摸你
I miss touching you.
我不知道沒有你在身邊該如何是好
I don't know how to not be around you.
我無時無刻不想著你
I think of you all the time.
都快要因此而恨你了
It almost makes me hate you for it.
我不知道該怎么辦
I don't know what to do.
你太美了
You're so beautiful.
-繼續說  -不僅是一般的美
- Keep going. - Not just beautiful, beautiful.
美人千千萬萬
There's lots of people like that.
你美得目眩  克萊爾
You are radiant, Claire.
而且善良  你太善良了
And good. You are so good.
-我不善良  -不  你是善良的
- I'm not good. - Yes, you are.
-你為什么不吻我  -我想看著你
- Why won't you kiss me? - I wanna look at you.
我真想有一天能去格陵蘭
I really do wanna go to Greenland one day.
-我們應該去  -別停
- We should go. - Don't stop.
冰天雪地  如此遙遠
It's so frozen and remote.
那里的
The way the...
那里的  氣味
The way the... Smells before it...
你知道我什么意思吧
The... You know what I mean?
救命  救命
Help. Help.
湯姆
Tom?
死亡人數將近五十萬
There are close to half a million dead.
有超過四百萬名難民
Over four million refugees,
背井離鄉  需要照料的婦女兒童
women and children who have left the region and require care.
流離失所的人至少有一千兩百萬
At least 12 million displaced people.
無處可去  無家可歸的流浪者
Homeless wanderers who no longer belong anywhere.
我們都學過歷史
We are all students of history.
敘利亞可是聯合國創始國之一
Syria was one of the founding members of the United Nations,
天吶
for God's sakes.
我們是怎么走到今天的
How did we get here?
我們來自最古老的文明之一
We, who sprang from one of the most ancient civilizations?
我們終得承認  和平才是唯一的答案
At some point, we must accept peace as the only answer.
各方必須放下武器  開始和談
All parties must lay down their arms and begin to talk.
好吧
Okay.
你總能找到我
You were always good at tracking me down.
很不容易
It wasn't easy.
電影院  偶爾的秘密會議
Movie theater, the occasional classified meeting.
我知道你在干什么
I know what you're doing.
這么說有點含糊
Well, that's a bit vague.
你是在給他搗亂  讓參議員倒戈
You're sabotaging him. Peeling off senators.
我知道是你干的
I know it's you.
你抽煙的時候要有趣得多
You were much more interesting when you smoked.
我沒有
No, I wasn't.
錢不在他那兒  馬克
The money's not with him, Mark.
科赫兄弟那些人  華爾街  石油天然氣
The... the Koch brother types, Wall Street, oil and gas...
連工人都要拋棄他了
Even labor's walking out on him.
他比你想得要神通廣大
He's more resourceful than you think.
沒有錢他也做了很多  好吧
He's done a lot without money, okay?
我要你別插手
I want you to back off,
讓我應付聽證會
let me handle these hearings.
我剛到白宮
I just got to the White House.
我想留下
I intend to stick around.
我不希望他當總統
I don't want him to be president.
-國家需要改變  -好  那么
- The country needs a change. - Okay, so...
有他妻子  就不用找其他人選了
And they don't need to look any further than his wife.
她堅韌又聰明
She's tough, smart.
他也很聰明  但他不可靠
He's smart, too, but he's not reliable.
至于她  你可以跟她合作
Her? You can work with her.
我知道你也清楚這一點
I know you see it, too.
敘利亞  或者滿目瘡痍的敘利亞
I see a partner when it comes to Syria,
可以成為合作伙伴
or what's left of it.
給我一個
Let me try one of those.
我們就不該
I mean, far be it from us
告訴一個古老的文明怎么處理它的問題
to tell an ancient civilization its business...
但現在  敘利亞是這世界上
but Syria is now basically unrivaled
-最暴力的地方  -我知道
- as the most violent place on the planet. - I know, I know.
我不是說  要拿弗蘭克·安德伍德怎么辦
I'm not saying what to do with Frank Underwood
不會成為一個巨大的麻煩
is not gonna be a difficult problem.
但  如果我們不在當地立足
But... if we don't establish a presence in the region...
那就太遲了
it's gonna be too late.
-我更想抽根煙  -吐出來吧
- I'd rather have a cigarette. - Spit it out.
讓我請你吃晚飯吧
Well... let me buy you dinner or something.
怎么  怎么了
What? What happened? What's the matter?
我抱著那孩子
I had that child in my arms.
我能感覺到她的呼吸
I could feel her breath on me,
但卻不敢往下看
but I couldn't look down.
失陪
Excuse me.
喂
Yeah?
20分鐘就到
20 minutes away.
-好  我得走了  抱歉  -去吧
- Okay. I have to go. I'm sorry. - Do, please.
我累了  我去睡了
I'm tired. I'm going to bed.
我需要你的服務
I need your services.
天吶
Jesus.
不
No.
馬上
Now.
我認為道格·斯坦普殺了佐伊·巴恩斯
I believe Doug Stamper killed Zoe Barnes.
我認為他情緒不穩定
I believe he was unstable
為了弗蘭西斯·安德伍德殺了她
and killed her to benefit Francis Underwood.
暫停  不要記錄
Stop. Stop it, please? Off the record.
能讓我們單獨待會兒嗎  我再叫你
Can you give us a second? I'll call you back in.
賽斯  這跟賄賂或卡拉比毫無關系
Seth, this has nothing to do with pay for play, or Kalabi,
跟其他任何總統受到的指控都無關
or anything else the president is accused of.
你想干什么
Where are you getting this?
這是我知道的道格的事
This is what I know about Doug.
主席不會允許
The chair will not let you
你在委員會前就此作證的
testify in front of the committee with this.
-我只有這些  -你能證明嗎
- This is what I have. - Can you prove any of it?
他暗示他那么做了
He's implied that he did it.
我可以闡述他的行為
I can speak to his behavior.
他做的事
Things that he's done.
你得去找聯邦檢察官
You need to go to the US attorney.
賽斯  否則  我會去的
Seth, if you don't, I will.
"我告訴總統  國務院追蹤了四個
"I told the president there were four men by the same name
同名的男子
the State Department was tracking.
兩個在美國境內"
Two in the United States."
這引述自一位資深白宮人士
So said a senior White House source,
由《華盛頓先驅報》刊登的
as quoted in the Washington Herald.
你是否知道這對話
Were you aware of this conversation?
不  先生  不知道
No, sir, I was not.
消息源還稱
The source went on.
"我認為總統知道
"I believe the president understood
田納西州的默罕默德·卡拉比
that the Muhammed Kalabi in Tennessee
并非真正的威脅"
was not a legitimate threat."
這你是否知道
Was this conveyed to you in any way?
還是不知道  先生
Again, no, sir.
委員會依然期待
Still, the committee's looking forward to
杜蘭特國務卿就此事作證
Secretary Durant's testimony on this matter.
我不知道國務卿會說什么  但是
I have no idea what the secretary will say or not say, but I...
我對她很尊敬  也祝愿她早日康復
have great respect for her and wish her a speedy recovery.
我們那天是依據
We were operating off of facts and
飛速涌入的事實和報告行動的
reports coming in at an accelerated rate that day.
我再問一次
I'll try this again.
總統是否曾向你暗示
Did the president indicate to you at any time
他知道這并非真正威脅
that he knew this was not a threat?
沒有
No.
而且我要說  我很驕傲
And I'd like to point out that I'm proud
今天能在此代表聯調局的男男女女
to be representing the men and women of the FBI here today,
他們像以往一樣進行了此案的調查
who conducted that investigation as they always do
得力  誠實  而且獨立
in a competent, honest, and independent way,
這是聯調局的優良傳統
in the finest tradition of the FBI.
-是嗎  -我們的人盡了職
- Did they? - Our people did their job.
認為聯調局會
And it's unthinkable to assume
卷入選舉根本是無稽之談
the FBI would involve itself in an election.
因為此時此刻可能有一個
Because there may be an innocent man
無辜的人正在蹲監獄
sitting in a cell as we speak.
我可以就此發表評論  因為報道中有提及
I can comment on this since it was mentioned in the press.
卡拉比先生的電腦上
Trace amounts of an explosive material
的確發現了痕量爆炸物
were found on Mr. Kalabi's computer.
你是說  總統不知道
Your assertion is that the president was unaware
自己的白宮里都發生了什么
of what was happening in his own White House?
艾丹·麥卡倫是國安局的雇員
Aidan Macallan was an NSA employee,
所以  不  總統不知道他都做了什么
so, no, the president had no idea what he was up to.
老實說  他當時在忙于競選
Honestly, he was quite busy campaigning.
但他肯定知道麥卡倫先生做的事的影響吧
But surely he knew the effects of Mr. Macallan's work?
這些漏洞
These exploits?
不知道
No.
總統  我是跟著他去巡回過的
The president and... I've been with him out on the stump.
他喜歡跟人握手
He likes to shake hands.
他并不關注社交媒體
He's not paying attention to social media.
哈維小姐  外國情報監視法法庭發布了一則判決
Ms. Harvey, there was a FISA ruling issued,
而安德伍德政府利用它
which the Underwood administration used
來監視美國公民
to spy on American citizens
意在影響選舉
for the sake of swaying an election.
羅梅洛議員  艾丹·麥卡倫是個有困擾的人
Congressman Romero, Aidan Macallan was a troubled person.
他的腦子轉得很快
His mind worked fast,
恐怕已超出了正常范圍
faster than I think anyone's should.
他的企圖已被他帶入墳墓
What he was up to went to the grave with him.
哈維小姐  少跟我打感情牌
Ms. Harvey, please, spare me the semantics...
-好吧  -我只需要你
- Okay, fine. - I just need you...
他收集數據了嗎  是的
Was he collecting data? Yes.
他過界了嗎  很可能
Did he cross a line? Most likely.
我去看過他  看他的工作
I did visit with him, checking in on his work.
你見過一屏的代碼嗎  電腦代碼
Have you seen a screen of code? Computer code.
那根本看不懂
It's indecipherable.
賽斯·格雷森怎么最終沒作證
Why did Seth Grayson end up not testifying?
無可評價
No comment.
我們聽說他的證詞
We heard that his testimony
跟總統的幕僚長有關
had to do with the president's chief of staff.
我很歡迎他來我們委員會作證
Who I would welcome testifying in front of our committee.
我敦促道格·斯坦普和其他政府人員
I urge Doug Stamper and the rest of the administration
別再躲在行政特權之后了
to stop hiding behind executive privilege.
我們目前只知道
All we learned so far is that
總統對他的白宮發生的事毫不知情
the president knew nothing about anything going on in his White House.
一共六個人
There were six of them,
他們輪流來
and they all took a turn.
除了羅梅洛
Except for Romero.
他只是看了
He only watched.
至少他是這么跟校長說的
Or... at least that's what he told the dean.
但我知道真相
But I know the real story.
她叫羅謝爾
Her name was, uh, Rochelle.
你不是沒有他的把柄嗎
I thought you had nothing on this guy.
你知道多久了
How long have you known this?
我是想留到我們需要的時候
I was holding it until... Or, if we needed it.
是你需要的時候吧
No, until you needed it, you mean.
這沒什么區別
Look, it makes no difference.
我可能會用  可能不會
I might use it, I might not.
但我還是想作證
But I still wanna testify.
你現在作證
For you to testify now,
抱歉  簡直瘋了
excuse me for saying it, it's crazy.
你覺得瘋了嗎  克萊爾
Do you think it's crazy, Claire?
-我想在他面前維護自己  -我們有證人
- I wanna defend myself against this guy. - We have witnesses.
我們的證人  代理人  讓他們說
Our witnesses, surrogates. Let it come from them.
我覺得我能贏
I think I can win.
或者我該等到我被參議院拋棄
Or maybe I should wait until I lose the Senate...
我就是覺得還有別的辦法
I just think there are other ways...
如果你放棄行政特權
If you give up executive privilege,
我們就喪失了籌碼  完全沒了
we lose leverage. We lose it all.
告訴主席  我愿作證了
Tell the chair I'm ready to appear.
你的證詞可能對你妻子造成的傷害
I mean, the damage your testimony could do to your wife
不值得冒險
is not worth the risk.
我們就是要討論它的價值
Its worth is what we're here to discuss.
我不喜歡由我來說  但是
I... I don't appreciate being the one to tell you this, but...
你的總統之位已經保不住了
your presidency is beyond repair.
你不知道我接下來要做什么
You don't know what I'm going to do next.
不是這個嗎  這才是讓你困擾的吧
Isn't that it? Isn't that what really bothers you?
別以為我沒從你加入的那一刻
Don't think I haven't been watching you
就在觀察你
from the moment you stepped on board.
你滿口承諾  戴維斯女士
You're full of promises, Ms. Davis.
麥卡倫的事仍未平息
The information about Macallan is still out there
而艾哈邁迪則神出鬼沒
and Ahmadi is, oh, so elusive.
你從走進我家
You've been sabotaging me
就一直在給我搗亂
from the moment you stepped into my house.
你不喜歡我  是吧
You don't care for me very much, do you?
是的
No, I don't.
我一點也不喜歡
I couldn't care less.
但如果你讓克萊爾開心  我就開心
But if you make Claire happy, that makes me happy.
如果你能好好幫她
If you can help her,
-那很好  -你愿付出什么
- good. - What's it worth to you?
你打算做什么樣的交易
Well, what kind of deal are we talking about?
要我不作證
For me not to testify.
我在華府外有人
Well, I have contacts outside the Beltway.
我可以給你找到各種肥差
I can set you up in any number of lucrative positions.
不  那不夠好
No, that's not good enough.
誰都能給我那個
Anyone could offer me that.
你說呢
You tell me.
不不  不能這樣
No, no, no. It's not going to work like that.
你說你能為我做什么
You tell me what you can do for me.
我接觸過你這樣的人
I've been around your kind.
一般沒接觸到這種深度
Not usually at this level.
但你就是忍不住
But you can't help yourself.
給我開價  戴維斯女士
Make me an offer, Ms. Davis.
你愿為她付出什么
What is she worth to you?
很多
A lot.
那么我是這么想的
So then here's what I'm thinking.
你是否莊嚴宣誓確認
Do you solemnly swear and affirm
你即將給出的證詞是真相
that the testimony you are about to give is the truth,
全部真相  絕無隱瞞
the whole truth, and nothing but the truth?
我宣誓
I do.
請記錄
Let the record reflect that
證人給出了肯定回答
the witness has answered in the affirmative.
總統先生  我想感謝你前來作證
Mr. President, I want to thank you for appearing...
希望我們可以為美國人民
and I hope we get to clear some things up
澄清一些事
for the American people.
總統先生  你可以開始
Mr. President, the floor is yours.
你想講多久都行
You can take as long or as short as you like.
如果你有書面聲明
If you have any written statement,
我們會在稍后將它納入記錄
we will include it after and it will be part of the record.
總統先生  請講
Mr. President, you are recognized.
謝謝  主席先生
Thank you, Mr. Chairman...
也感謝其他委員會成員
and to the other members of this committee.
我今天同意在委員會面前作證
I have agreed to appear before this committee today...
是因為
because...
我有罪
I'm guilty.
我花了30年的人生
Guilty of having spent the last 30 years of my life
在這里
here...
在國會
in this Congress.
在眾議院
In this House.
然后成為副總統  總統
Then as vice president and now as president,
只為效力于人民
trying to do the people's work.
委員會指控我犯下了很多事
Now, this committee has accused me of a great number of things.
你們指控我賄賂
You accused me of pay to play.
那么我也指控你們犯下了同樣罪行
And so I accuse you of exactly the same.
我還指控你們只為自己的利益行使政治手段
I also accuse you of playing politics only when it suits you.
你們都拿了錢
You're all being paid.
你們都有要效力的主子
You're all serving some master.
你們每個人
Each and every one of you,
你們知道我所言不虛
and you know I know that for a fact.
比如你  羅梅洛議員
You, for example, Congressman Romero...
你扳倒我的不懈努力  是為了正義嗎
and your crusade to take me down, is it for justice?
為了國家嗎
For the good of the nation?
你真的是想要真相嗎
Is the truth what you're really after?
還是為了個人利益
Or is it for some personal gain?
或許是為了填補
Perhaps to try to fill
你很久之前賣掉的
the small hole in your soul
那一塊靈魂留下的空洞
that you sold off a long time ago?
-總統先生  -不  不  不
- Mr. President. - No, no, no.
這是我的開場陳述
This is my opening statement,
我要說完
and I will give it in full.
我還沒說完  女士們先生們
I am not done, ladies and gentlemen.
你們指控我違反規則
You accuse me of breaking the rules,
我告訴你們  我完全遵守規則
and I tell you, I am playing by the rules.
正是你們和我一起達成的規則
The very rules that you and I all agreed upon.
正是你們和我
The very rules that you and I
一起寫的規則
all wrote together.
是的  我非常有罪
So, yes, I'm guilty as hell,
但你們也都有罪
but then so are all of you.
是的  體制有問題
Yes, the system is corrupt,
但你們想要我這樣的人守門
but you wanted a guardian at the gate like me.
為什么呢
And why?
因為你們知道
Because you know
我會不惜一切
I will do whatever it takes.
你們都喜歡這樣
And you have all enjoyed it,
參與其中  并從中獲利
been party to it and benefited by it.
別否認  你喜歡的
Don't deny it. You've loved it.
你并不需要我堅持什么
You don't actually need me to stand for anything.
你只希望我站出來
You just need me to stand.
希望我強勢
To be the strong man.
希望我采取行動
The man of action.
天吶  你好喜歡行動和口號
My God, you're addicted to action and slogans.
不管我說了什么
It doesn't matter what I say.
我做了什么
It doesn't matter what I do.
只要我有所作為
Just as long as I'm doing something,
你就樂意跟著走
you're happy to be along for the ride.
老實說  我不怪你
And frankly, I don't blame you.
你生活中有那么多愚蠢和猶豫
With all the foolishness and indecision in your lives,
為什么不要個我這樣的人
why not a man like me?
我不道歉
I don't apologize.
最終  我不在意你是愛我還是恨我
In the end, I don't care whether you love me or you hate me,
只要我贏就行
just as long as I win.
結局早被安排好  規則是被操縱的
The deck is stacked. The rules are rigged.
歡迎來到理智時代的終結
Welcome to the death of the Age of Reason.
已經沒有是非了
There is no right or wrong. Not anymore.
只有入局
There's only being in...
和出局
and then being out.
所以我不要再參與其中了
So I will not be party to this any longer.
我不要再替你們背負罵名了
I will not wear the target for any of you anymore.
你們都已經利用我太久了
You have all used me far long enough.
所以派對結束  旅程結束
So, the party's over, the ride's done.
我太尊重這一職位
I respect the office too much
不能允許這繼續下去
to allow this to continue going on.
所以我要向委員會和全國人民宣布
That's why I am announcing to this committee and to the nation
明晚6點起
that as of 6:00 p.m. tomorrow evening,
我將辭去美國總統一職
I shall resign the office of President of the United States.
秩序
Order!
屆時我樂意回答你們的一切問題
And I will be happy to take any questions you may have.
但我的直覺是  已經沒那個必要了
But my gut tells me that isn't really going to be necessary.
聽證會作證有兩個類型
一種要求證人宣誓  宣誓后如果說謊  就是違法行為
另一種不宣誓  有不實之言不用負法律責任
如果被發現宣誓后說謊  可能被國會表決定為"蔑視國會"
但位高權重之人  往往也只受到書面譴責  并不一定真的會被起訴
普通人則不敢冒險
國會有發傳票的權力  收到傳票的人按法律規定需要服從
但如果不服從  并不會直接受到懲罰
往往是  如果在接受調查時不配合  那么可能會導致司法介入
然后走法律程序  被起訴定罪
同樣  如果國會在調查后發現被調查者有違法行為
那么相關的司法部門會隨即介入  進行進一步的起訴  定罪
也就是說  國會調查很嚴重  但并不能代替法律程序